<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Leigh Appel</title><link href="http://www.leighappel.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.leighappel.com/feeds/Programming.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.leighappel.com/</id><updated>2013-06-17T00:00:00+10:00</updated><entry><title>Blog Status Update!</title><link href="http://www.leighappel.com/blog-status-update.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-06-17T00:00:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Leigh</name></author><id>tag:www.leighappel.com,2013-06-17:blog-status-update.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;No, the blog is not dead! I have just been really busy. This post is mostly an update on what I have been up to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what have I been up to? Well, apart from all the regular duties a life entails, it's three things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Matasano crypto challenges!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've started a podcast!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm bootstrapping a start up!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of these things has conspired to interfere with a regular blogging regime. Let me explain a little about each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.matasano.com/articles/crypto-challenges/"&gt;Matasano Crypto Challenges!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those of you who are not aware of Matasano I'll let you check them out &lt;a href="www.matasano.com"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I have followed these guys for a long time, mostly in admiration and jealousy (just read their careers page to understand why).  I also follow the commentary of one of their esteemed co-founders &lt;a href="www.twitter.com/tqbf"&gt;@tqbf&lt;/a&gt; who happens to be a great commenter on hacker news. A lot of his posts are quite interesting and I seem to learn something new everytime I read one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While browsing hacker news one day I stumbled upon a blog post which detailed an account of undertaking the Matasano Crypto Challenges (The blog post is &lt;a href="https://blog.pinboard.in/2013/04/the_matasano_crypto_challenges/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and is quite good). Needless to say, but I'll say it anyway, I was hooked.  So far I have spent about 20+ hours on the challenges and am currently up to round 3, question 21ish.  I decided to undertake these problems in python, mostly as a way of solidifying my knowledge of a language I am relatively new too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am hoping to find time to finish the 3rd set at least and I highly reccommend everyone who is interested in programming, security, cryptography or learning new things take up the challenge, it is extremely rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They do not want people to post their solutions so I wont. But if anyone wants to chat about the problems themselves or compare notes/solutions I would be very glad too. I currently only know one other person doing them and would love to share and speak with more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href="www.hackandheckle.com"&gt;I've Started a podcast!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this one is exciting, myself along with two other programmers based in Brisbane (&lt;a href="www.twitter.com/darrenrogan"&gt;@darrenrogan&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="www.twitter.com/benedwinmorgan"&gt;@benedwinmorgan&lt;/a&gt;) have started a podcast!  The podcast is mostly about tech news, programming and the meetup scene is Brisbane, but may touch on any number of things that interest us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is titled Hack and Heckle and the website is at (www.hackandheckle.com). Please check us out and have a listen, we need feedback and questions! We are also hoping to interview some local tech notables, so if you have any suggestions let us know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;I'm bootstrapping a side project!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final and certainly most significant thing that has begun to develop is the beginning of a side project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently I am the sole backend engineer and have been using and enjoying &lt;a href="https://www.djangoproject.com"&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; + the very cool &lt;a href="http://django-rest-framework.org/"&gt;Django REST Framework&lt;/a&gt; deployed to &lt;a href="aws.amazon.com"&gt;Amazon Web Services&lt;/a&gt; I have also been helping out in the frontend for which we are using &lt;a href="emberjs.com"&gt;Ember.js&lt;/a&gt;.  Currently we arn't speaking about it in public as we are in full development but stay tuned as there may be more news to follow.  I will at least attempt to chronicle my use of the technologies.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="programming"></category><category term="clojure"></category></entry><entry><title>Processing.js, Conway's Game of Life and Code Kata</title><link href="http://www.leighappel.com/processingjs-conways-game-of-life-and-code-kata.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-18T00:00:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Leigh</name></author><id>tag:www.leighappel.com,2013-02-18:processingjs-conways-game-of-life-and-code-kata.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;script src="static/javascript/processing.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently revisted the &lt;a href="http://processing.org"&gt;Processing&lt;/a&gt; language/framework.  I had previously used processing when working on projects with my Arduino.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the latest developments is that of &lt;a href="http://processingjs.org"&gt;Processing.js&lt;/a&gt; which brings your processing projects to the web. So I managed to knock something up to test it out. It was also an example of a problem I used for code kata the other day, Conway's Game of Life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code can be found on my github &lt;a href="https://www.github.com/abarax/game-of-life"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Feel free to critique, constructive criticism is always welcome, everything is an exercise in learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;canvas data-processing-sources="static/code/game.pde"&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;</summary><category term="processing"></category></entry></feed>